<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>



<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://wildfly.org//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://wildfly.org//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2021-06-18T11:44:45+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://wildfly.org/</id>

  
  
    <title type="html">WildFly</title>
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">WildFly 24 is released!</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/17/WildFly24-Final-Released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WildFly 24 is released!" />
      <published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/17/WildFly24-Final-Released</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/17/WildFly24-Final-Released/">&lt;div id=&quot;preamble&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m pleased to announce that the WildFly 24 Final zip is now available &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildfly.org/downloads&quot;&gt;for download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work during the WildFly 24 development cycle has been primarily oriented toward bug fixing, plus the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/04/29/WildFly2302-Released/&quot;&gt;Jakarta EE 9.1 certification work done for WildFly 23&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#8217;ve also been doing work on getting WildFly Preview to run well on SE 16 and 17, with a goal of being able to support SE 17 in standard WildFly later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of new features in 24 though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MicroProfile Reactive Streams Operators subsystem has been updated to support &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse/microprofile-reactive-streams-operators/releases/tag/2.0&quot;&gt;version 2.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-proposals/blob/main/elytron/WFCORE-5027-charset-encoding-support.adoc&quot;&gt;specify the character set and hash encoding&lt;/a&gt; strings to verify client-supplied passwords against passwords stored in a Properties Realm, Filesystem Realm, JDBC Realm and LDAP realm in the Elytron subsystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older JDK versions use the protocol &lt;code&gt;SSLv2Hello&lt;/code&gt; in the initial handshake message where the SSL version that will be used for the rest of the handshake is negotiated. Although the use of this protocol is discouraged and disabled by default in newer JDK versions, in order to ensure feature parity with legacy security configurations it is now possible to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-proposals/blob/main/elytron/WFCORE-5145-ssl-allowed-protocols.adoc&quot;&gt;configure a client or server SSL context using the
&lt;code&gt;SSLv2Hello&lt;/code&gt; protocol&lt;/a&gt; in the Elytron subsystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elytron previously supported configuring one certificate revocation list. However, if several Certificate Authorities were used, there was no
way to configure more than one certificate revocation file. It is now possible to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-proposals/blob/main/elytron/WFCORE-5170-multiple-certificate-revocation-lists.adoc&quot;&gt;configure multiple certificate revocation lists&lt;/a&gt; in Elytron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/quickstart/tree/24.0.0.Final/todo-backend&quot;&gt;new quickstart&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;todo-backend&lt;/code&gt; showcases how WildFly can be deployed on OpenShift to provide a backend that exposes an HTTP API (using Jakarta RESTful Web Services) and stores data to a DB (using Jakarta Persistence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;codehaus-jackson-removal&quot;&gt;Codehaus Jackson Removal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that in WildFly 24 we&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/WFLY-14672&quot;&gt;removed the Codehaus Jackson libraries&lt;/a&gt; from the server distribution, along with support for the Jakarta RESTful Web Services provider that used Codehaus Jackson. For many years now a provider based on the successor FasterXML Jackson project has been available and is the preferred option for those wanting to use Jackson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wildfly-preview&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wildfly.org/news/2020/11/12/Jakarta-EE-9-with-WildFly-Preview/&quot;&gt;announced in November&lt;/a&gt; when we released WildFly 22 Alpha1, along with our traditional Jakarta EE 8 distribution we want to give our users a preview of what will be coming in WildFly as we move on to EE 9 and later. We call this distribution &quot;WildFly Preview&quot;. The WildFly 24.0.0.Final release includes an update to WildFly Preview. &lt;em&gt;Even though this is coming from a .Final tag of the WildFly codebase, WildFly Preview should always be regarded as a tech-preview/beta distribution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EE 9 is primarily about implementing the necessary change in the Jakarta EE APIs from the javax.* package namespace to the jakarta.* namespace. This is a big change that is going to take a while to percolate through the EE ecosystem, e.g. for the many projects that compile against the EE APIs to provide versions that use jakarta.*. While this happens we want to continue to deliver new features and fixes to our community, so the primary WildFly distribution will continue to provide the EE 8 APIs. This will continue at least through WildFly 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;standards-support&quot;&gt;Standards Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard WildFly 24.0.0 distribution is a Jakarta EE 8 compatible implementation, compatible with both the Full Platform and the Web Profile. Evidence supporting our certification is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE8/WildFly_24.0.0.Final/jakarta-full-platform.adoc#tck-results&quot;&gt;for the Full Platform&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE8/WildFly_24.0.0.Final/jakarta-web-profile.adoc#tck-results&quot;&gt;for the Web Profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with WildFly 23 we are exclusively focusing on the Jakarta EE test suite for EE certification / compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard WildFly 24 distribution is also a compliant implementation of the MicroProfile 4.0 platform specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WildFly Preview distribution released today is a compatible implementation of both the Jakarta EE 9.1 Web Profile and the Full Platform.  Evidence supporting our certification is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9.1/WildFly_24.0.0.Final/jakarta-full-platform.adoc#tck-results&quot;&gt;for the Full Platform&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9.1/WildFly_24.0.0.Final/jakarta-web-profile.adoc#tck-results&quot;&gt;for the Web Profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jdk-support&quot;&gt;JDK Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our recommendation is that you run WildFly on the most recent long-term support JDK release, i.e. on JDK 11 for WildFly 24. While we do do some testing of WildFly on JDK 13, we do considerably more testing of WildFly itself on the LTS JDKs, and we make no attempt to ensure the projects producing the various libraries we integrate are testing their libraries on anything other than JDK 8 or 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly 24 also is heavily tested and runs well on Java 8. We plan to continue to support Java 8 at least through WildFly 25, and probably beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we recommend using an LTS JDK release, I do believe WildFly runs well on JDK 13. By run well, I mean the main WildFly testsuite runs with no more than a few failures in areas not expected to be commonly used. We want developers who are trying to evaluate what a newer JVM means for their applications to be able to look to WildFly as a useful development platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major focus during the WildFly 24 development cycle was on identifying and addressing issues related to running WildFly on JDK 16 and the early access releases of JDK 17. JDK 17 is due out in September and will be the next LTS JDK release, so we want to be ready to support it as soon as we can. I&amp;#8217;m pleased to be able to say that the 24.0.0.Final release of WildFly Preview runs well on SE 16 and the SE 17 early access release for most use cases. The main use case where we still have some issues to resolve relate to Hibernate&amp;#8217;s proxy generation, but these don&amp;#8217;t prevent JPA from working well in general. For developers wanting to get a sense of what SE 17 will mean for their applications, I encourage you to give WildFly Preview 24 a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard WildFly does not run well on SE 14 or later because the security implementation used in our standard configurations will not work on SE 14 or later. However if you want to experiment with standard WildFly 24 on the latest SE, you can try starting with the configuration files provided in WildFly Preview, which do not use the legacy security subsystem. This has not been heavily tested, so YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that WildFly runs on Java 11 and later in classpath mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;upcoming-changes&quot;&gt;Upcoming Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with WildFly 25 there will be some significant changes coming in WildFly, primarily related to moving completely to Elytron-based security and away from the legacy security implementation. Significant changes you can expect to see include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removal of the legacy security subsystem from the standard configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removal of support for the security vault, with Elytron credential stores as the replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removal of the core management security realms from the standard configurations, with Elytron subsystem resources used instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removal of the Picketlink extension and the subsystems it provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potentially the Picketbox libraries will no longer be available, making the legacy security subsystem and core management security realms unavailable altogether on a server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to security, &quot;legacy feature packs&quot; (which use a provisioning technology that predates Galleon) will no longer be distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re also evaluating changes in domain mode to limit the set of older version Host Controllers a current Domain Controller must be able to support, reducing the set to some of the more recent WildFly versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WildFly 24 documentation is available at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/24/&quot;&gt;docs.wildfly.org site&lt;/a&gt;. The WildFly 24 management API documentation is in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/24/wildscribe&quot;&gt;wildscribe section of the WildFly 24 docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jira-release-notes&quot;&gt;Jira Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of issues resolved is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12313721&amp;amp;version=12358082&quot;&gt;in the WFLY JIRA project&lt;/a&gt;. Issues resolved in the WildFly Core 16 release included with WildFly 24 are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12315422&amp;amp;version=12358650&quot;&gt;in the WFCORE JIRA project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;enjoy&quot;&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continued support of WildFly.  We&amp;#8217;d love to hear your feedback at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/wildfly&quot;&gt;WildFly forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Brian Stansberry</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="announcement" />
      
        <category term="release" />
      
        <category term="microprofile" />
      
        <category term="jakartaee" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I&amp;#8217;m pleased to announce that the WildFly 24 Final zip is now available for download.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">How to Change Logging Level for WildFly on the Cloud</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/15/change-log-level-wildfly-cloud/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Change Logging Level for WildFly on the Cloud" />
      <published>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/15/change-log-level-wildfly-cloud</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/15/change-log-level-wildfly-cloud/">&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your WildFly application is running on the Cloud (on Kubernetes, OpenShift or any other container platform) and starts to behave unexpectedly, it is useful to be able to change the logging of the server to display debug logs to get a better insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will walkthrough a very simple script that can be used to change the logging level of a WildFly server in an application image on the (wild) fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wildfly-management-commands&quot;&gt;WildFly Management Commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, the WildFly server is configured to display &lt;code&gt;INFO&lt;/code&gt; logs on the console.
These logs are the output displayed by the command &lt;code&gt;kubectl logs &amp;lt;pod&amp;gt;)&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ kubectl logs wildfly-s2i-app-8f8b49957-b7xbk
...
08:10:40,347 INFO  [org.jboss.as] (Controller Boot Thread) WFLYSRV0025: WildFly Full 23.0.2.Final (WildFly Core 15.0.1.Final) started in 15658ms - Started 288 of 383 services (156 services are lazy, passive or on-demand)
08:10:40,348 INFO  [org.jboss.as] (Controller Boot Thread) WFLYSRV0060: Http management interface listening on http://0.0.0.0:9990/management
08:10:40,348 INFO  [org.jboss.as] (Controller Boot Thread) WFLYSRV0054: Admin console is not enabled&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we need to change the logging level to display debug logs, we can use the &lt;code&gt;jboss-cli.sh&lt;/code&gt; script located in the WildFly server directory to execute two management commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ kubectl exec -it  wildfly-s2i-app-8f8b49957-b7xbk -- sh
sh-4.2$ $JBOSS_HOME/bin/jboss-cli.sh -c
[standalone@localhost:9990 /] /subsystem=logging/console-handler=CONSOLE:write-attribute(name=level,value=DEBUG)
{&quot;outcome&quot; =&amp;gt; &quot;success&quot;}
[standalone@localhost:9990 /] /subsystem=logging/root-logger=ROOT:write-attribute(name=level,value=DEBUG)
{&quot;outcome&quot; =&amp;gt; &quot;success&quot;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that change, we can no see &lt;code&gt;DEBUG&lt;/code&gt; logs in the console output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ kubectl logs wildfly-s2i-app-8f8b49957-b7xbk
...
08:26:35,002 DEBUG [io.undertow.request] (default I/O-2) Matched default handler path /config/value
08:26:35,004 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.resteasy_jaxrs.i18n] (default task-1) RESTEASY002315: PathInfo: /config/value
08:26:35,005 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.cdi.i18n] (default task-1) RESTEASY010520: Beans found for class org.wildfly.quickstarts.microprofile.config.ConfigResour
ce : [Managed Bean [class org.wildfly.quickstarts.microprofile.config.ConfigResource] with qualifiers [@Any @Default]]
08:26:35,006 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.resteasy_jaxrs.i18n] (default task-1) MessageBodyWriter: org.jboss.resteasy.spi.ResteasyProviderFactory$SortedKey
08:26:35,006 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.resteasy_jaxrs.i18n] (default task-1) MessageBodyWriter: org.jboss.resteasy.plugins.providers.StringTextStar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jboss_home-environment-variable&quot;&gt;JBOSS_HOME environment variable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These commands work fine when the application image has been built with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-s2i&quot;&gt;WildFly S2I&lt;/a&gt; as the &lt;code&gt;JBOSS_HOME&lt;/code&gt; environment variable is set and we can invoke &lt;code&gt;$JBOSS_HOME/bin/jboss-cli.sh&lt;/code&gt; without any issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However if the application image has been built with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/bootablejar/&quot;&gt;Bootable Jar&lt;/a&gt;, there is no &lt;code&gt;JBOSS_HOME&lt;/code&gt; as the server will be unzipped when the container is started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we then determine the actual location of the server?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the container image is started, a special file is created at &lt;code&gt;/opt/jboss/container/wildfly-bootable-jar/install-dir&lt;/code&gt; whose content is the actual location of the unzipped WildFly server for &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; specific pod:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ kubectl exec -it wildfly-bootable-jar-app-7cf8bdc95c-j9mjk -- sh
sh-4.4$ cat /opt/jboss/container/wildfly-bootable-jar/install-dir
/tmp/wildfly-bootable-server15112249313411534387&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that knowledge, we can update our script to set the value of the &lt;code&gt;JBOSS_HOME&lt;/code&gt; environment with the content of that file if it exists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;sh-4.4$ [ -e /opt/jboss/container/wildfly-bootable-jar/install-dir ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; JBOSS_HOME=$( cat /opt/jboss/container/wildfly-bootable-jar/install-dir )
sh-4.4$ echo $JBOSS_HOME
/tmp/wildfly-bootable-server15112249313411534387&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;change-log-level-script&quot;&gt;change-log-level Script&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now write a very simple script that can be used to change the global logging level one any WildFly application image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jmesnil/78581f90c68f84ba9240ef48f627ff45&quot; class=&quot;bare&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/jmesnil/78581f90c68f84ba9240ef48f627ff45&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and is straigthforward to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ wget https://gist.githubusercontent.com/jmesnil/78581f90c68f84ba9240ef48f627ff45/raw/062b3f1a8f7cf6e85b233e69348c97d006003a92/change-log-level
$ chmod u+x change-log-level

$ ./change-log-level

change-log-level is a script to change the logging level of the WildFly server inside an application image running on any Kubernetes cluster.
Usage:
  change-log-level &amp;lt;pod&amp;gt; &amp;lt;logging-level&amp;gt;
Where the parameters are:
  * &amp;lt;pod&amp;gt; - Name of the pod running the application image
  * &amp;lt;logging-level&amp;gt; - The logging level to set (can be one of ALL, FINEST, FINER, TRACE, DEBUG, FINE, CONFIG, INFO
    WARN, WARNING, ERROR, SEVERE, FATAL, OFF)

$ ./change-log-level wildfly-bootable-jar-app-7cf8bdc95c-j9mjk DEBUG
Change logging level to TRACE for WildFly server in wildfly-microprofile-config-app-7cf8bdc95c-j9mjk
[standalone@localhost:9990 /] /subsystem=logging/console-handler=CONSOLE:write-attribute(name=level,value=DEBUG)
{&quot;outcome&quot; =&amp;gt; &quot;success&quot;}
[standalone@localhost:9990 /] /subsystem=logging/root-logger=ROOT:write-attribute(name=level,value=DEBUG)
{&quot;outcome&quot; =&amp;gt; &quot;success&quot;}

$ kubectl logs wildfly-bootable-jar-app-7cf8bdc95c-j9mjk
10:14:10,380 DEBUG [io.undertow.request] (default I/O-1) Matched default handler path /
10:14:10,381 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.resteasy_jaxrs.i18n] (default task-1) RESTEASY002315: PathInfo: /
10:14:10,382 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.cdi.i18n] (default task-1) RESTEASY010520: Beans found for class org.wildfly.quickstarts.microprofile.config.RootResource
 : [Managed Bean [class org.wildfly.quickstarts.microprofile.config.RootResource] with qualifiers [@Any @Default]]
10:14:10,393 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.plugins.validation.i18n] (default task-1) RESTEASY008510: ResteasyCdiExtension is on the classpath.
10:14:10,394 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.resteasy_jaxrs.i18n] (default task-1) MessageBodyWriter: org.jboss.resteasy.spi.ResteasyProviderFactory$SortedKey
10:14:10,394 DEBUG [org.jboss.resteasy.resteasy_jaxrs.i18n] (default task-1) MessageBodyWriter: org.jboss.resteasy.plugins.providers.StringTextStar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonitionblock note&quot;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Note&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script is doing a brute-force switch of the root logger and will change the log level of &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; loggers in the WildFly server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more realistic case, you would have to adapt the management commands to change the log level on more specific loggers related to your application to reduce the noise from other loggers. This can easily be done by updating the script and changing the commands from the &lt;code&gt;WILDFLY_COMMANDS&lt;/code&gt; property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simple script is useful to be able to change the logging of the server to display debug logs to get a better insight.
It can be used as the basis to run any kind of management commands on WildFly in an application image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Jeff Mesnil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="wildfly" />
      
        <category term="logging" />
      
        <category term="cloud" />
      
        <category term="openshift" />
      
        <category term="kubernetes" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">When your WildFly application is running on the Cloud (on Kubernetes, OpenShift or any other container platform) and starts to behave unexpectedly, it is useful to be able to change the logging of the server to display debug logs to get a better insight.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">WildFly 24 Beta1 is released!</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/04/WildFly24-Beta-Released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WildFly 24 Beta1 is released!" />
      <published>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/04/WildFly24-Beta-Released</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/06/04/WildFly24-Beta-Released/">&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m pleased to announce that the new WildFly and WildFly Preview 24.0.0.Beta1 releases are available for download at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildfly.org/downloads&quot; class=&quot;bare&quot;&gt;https://wildfly.org/downloads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work during the WildFly 24 development cycle has been primarily oriented toward bug fixing, plus the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/04/29/WildFly2302-Released/&quot;&gt;Jakarta EE 9.1 certification work done for WildFly 23&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do want to express my special thanks to Sonia Zaldana, a great contributor to WildFly over the past year, who has added three new features in WildFly 24 Beta1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/WFCORE-5027&quot;&gt;Security Realm support for specifying the charset and encoding for credentials.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/WFCORE-5145&quot;&gt;Additional Elytron server-ssl-context allowed protocols.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/WFCORE-5170&quot;&gt;Certificate revocation lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other area of focus during this development cycle was improving how WildFly, particularly WildFly Preview, runs on JDK 16 and the early access releases of the next LTS JDK release, JDK 17. There are still some issues to resolve, but WildFly Preview 24 Beta1 runs well enough on the latest JDKs that it&amp;#8217;s worthwhile for people interested in what JDK 17 will mean for their application to give it a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release notes for the release are &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12313721&amp;amp;version=12352775&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, with issues fixed in the underlying WildFly Core betas listed &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20WFCORE%20AND%20statusCategory%20%3D%20Done%20AND%20fixVersion%20in%20(16.0.0.Beta1%2C%2016.0.0.Beta2%2C%2016.0.0.Beta3%2C%2016.0.0.Beta4%2C%2016.0.0.Beta5)%20ORDER%20BY%20issuetype%20DESC%2C%20key%20ASC%2C%20priority%20DESC&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please try it out and give us your feedback, while we get to work WildFly 24 Final!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Brian Stansberry</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="announcement" />
      
        <category term="release" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I&amp;#8217;m pleased to announce that the new WildFly and WildFly Preview 24.0.0.Beta1 releases are available for download at https://wildfly.org/downloads.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Helm Chart for WildFly</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/05/05/helm-charts-for-wildfly/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Helm Chart for WildFly" />
      <published>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/05/05/helm-charts-for-wildfly</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/05/05/helm-charts-for-wildfly/">&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://helm.sh&quot;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that helps define, install and upgrade complex applications on Kubernetes clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have now released a Helm Chart for WildFly to help our users build and deploy WildFly applications on OpenShift that leverages all the innovative features provided by the WildFly ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;wildfly&lt;/code&gt; Chart can be used to achieve two objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;build an application image from a Git repository containing a Java project. This step leverages WildFly features such as Galleon provisioning or Bootable Jar to provide the fittest image for your application requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deploy an application image with all the resources and configuration needed to integrate it on OpenShift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, the two steps are connected: the &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; step&amp;#8217;s output is an application image that becomes the input of the &lt;code&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; step.
However, it is possible to enable or disable these steps: if you have another way to build your application image, you can disable the &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; step and still deploy it by specifying where your application image can be pulled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the chart configuration is described in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/blob/main/charts/wildfly/README.md&quot;&gt;Chart documentation&lt;/a&gt;.
In this post, we will focus on a simple MicroProfile application to show you how the Helm chart simplifies its deployment on OpenShift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;microprofile-application-example&quot;&gt;MicroProfile Application Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use one WildFly quickstart as an example: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/quickstart/tree/master/microprofile-config&quot;&gt;microprofile-config&lt;/a&gt;.
We will not cover the code of this example but the important things to mention are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application will be running as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/bootablejar/&quot;&gt;WildFly Bootable Jar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses MicroProfile API and provides a HTTP endpoint. A WildFly server will be provisioned with the &lt;code&gt;jaxrs-server&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;microprofile-platform&lt;/code&gt; layers so that server contains all the bits (and only those!) to run these features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its HTTP endpoint uses MicroProfile Config to read a config property from the &lt;code&gt;CONFIG_PROP&lt;/code&gt; environment variable and returns its value in the HTTP response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-helm-and-have-access-to-an-openshift-cluster&quot;&gt;Install Helm and have access to an OpenShift cluster.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://helm.sh/docs/intro/install/&quot;&gt;Installing Helm&lt;/a&gt; page to install Helm in your environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.redhat.com/developer-sandbox&quot;&gt;Developer Sandbox for Red Hat OpenShift&lt;/a&gt; as our OpenShift cluster and make sure that we are logged in the cluster and that the &lt;code&gt;oc&lt;/code&gt; command applies to that cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-helm-repository-for-wildfly-chart&quot;&gt;Install Helm Repository for WildFly Chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;wildfly&lt;/code&gt; Chart can be installed from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/wildfly-charts/&quot; class=&quot;bare&quot;&gt;https://docs.wildfly.org/wildfly-charts/&lt;/a&gt; repository&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ helm repo add wildfly https://docs.wildfly.org/wildfly-charts/
&quot;wildfly&quot; has been added to your repositories
$ helm search repo wildfly
NAME                    CHART VERSION   APP VERSION     DESCRIPTION
wildfly/wildfly         1.3.0           23.0            Build and Deploy WildFly applications on OpenShift&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to notice is that the &lt;code&gt;APP VERSION&lt;/code&gt; points to &lt;code&gt;23.0&lt;/code&gt;. By default, the Chart will deploy your application using the latest WildFly 23.0 release (23.0.2.Final at the time of this writing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-the-application-on-openshift&quot;&gt;Install the Application on OpenShift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the &lt;code&gt;wildfly&lt;/code&gt; Chart is added, we can instal a Helm &lt;strong&gt;release&lt;/strong&gt; by using the &lt;code&gt;helm install&lt;/code&gt; command with the name of the release as well as a YAML configuration file that contains all the settings to build and deploy the application:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ helm install microprofile-config-app \
    wildfly/wildfly \
    -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/main/examples/microprofile-config/microprofile-config-app.yaml

NAME: microprofile-config-app
LAST DEPLOYED: Tue May  4 14:52:02 2021
NAMESPACE: jmesnil1-dev
STATUS: deployed
REVISION: 1
TEST SUITE: None
NOTES:
Your WildFly appplication is building! To follow the build, run:

$ oc get build -w

Note that your Deployment will report &quot;ErrImagePull&quot; and &quot;ImagePullBackOff&quot; until the build is complete. Once the build is complete, your image will be automatically rolled out.

To follow the deployment of your application, run:

$ oc get deployment microprofile-config-app -w&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can read above, the ouput of the &lt;code&gt;helm install&lt;/code&gt; command contains instructions to follow the installation of the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can watch its build by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ oc get build -w
NAME                        TYPE     FROM          STATUS    STARTED         DURATION
microprofile-config-app-1   Source   Git@7f0eed5   Running   2 minutes ago
microprofile-config-app-1   Source   Git@7f0eed5   Complete   4 minutes ago   4m30s&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the application is built, we can watch its deployment by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ oc get deployment microprofile-config-app -w
NAME                      READY   UP-TO-DATE   AVAILABLE   AGE
microprofile-config-app   0/1     1            0           4m4s
microprofile-config-app   0/1     1            0           4m30s
microprofile-config-app   1/1     1            1           5m17s&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is now available and we can query it.
By default, the Helm Chart will create a &lt;code&gt;Route&lt;/code&gt; to access the application:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ oc get route
NAME                      HOST/PORT                                                                        PATH   SERVICES                  PORT    TERMINATION     WILDCARD
microprofile-config-app   microprofile-config-app-jmesnil1-dev.apps.sandbox-m2.ll9k.p1.openshiftapps.com          microprofile-config-app   &amp;lt;all&amp;gt;   edge/Redirect   None&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonitionblock note&quot;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Note&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;HOST/PORT&lt;/code&gt; value is specific to my cluster and your route will have a different value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can then query the HTTP endpoint by using this information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ curl -L  http://$(oc get route microprofile-config-app -o jsonpath=&quot;{.spec.host}&quot;)/config/value
Hello from OpenShift&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is up and running.
Let&amp;#8217;s now look at the configuration file that the Chart used to install the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-at-the-helm-release-file&quot;&gt;Looking at the Helm Release File&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s deep dive in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/main/examples/microprofile-config/microprofile-config-app.yaml&quot;&gt;YAML File&lt;/a&gt; that we use to install the application (&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/main/examples/microprofile-config/microprofile-config-app.yaml&quot; class=&quot;bare&quot;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/main/examples/microprofile-config/microprofile-config-app.yaml&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;build:
  uri: https://github.com/wildfly/quickstart.git
  ref: 23.0.2.SP1
  mode: bootable-jar
  env:
  - name: ARTIFACT_DIR
    value: microprofile-config/target
  - name: MAVEN_ARGS_APPEND
    # Use the bootable-jar-openshift profile to ensure that the application
    # can be deployed on OpenShift but disable JKube as the image will be
    # built and deployed by this chart.
    value: -am -pl microprofile-config -Pbootable-jar-openshift -Djkube.skip=true
  - name: MAVEN_OPTS
    value: '-XX:MetaspaceSize=251m -XX:MaxMetaspaceSize=256m'
deploy:
  replicas: 1
  env:
  - name: CONFIG_PROP
    value: Hello from OpenShift&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to notice is that the configuration file contains two main sections &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; section focuses on building the application image using an OpenShift &lt;code&gt;BuildConfig&lt;/code&gt; resource.
The &lt;code&gt;BuildConfig&lt;/code&gt; resource pulls the application from a Git repository (based on the &lt;code&gt;uri&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ref&lt;/code&gt; fields).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;mode&lt;/code&gt; field specifies which types of application image to build. There are two valid modes: &lt;code&gt;s2i&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bootable-jar&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;s2i&lt;/code&gt; build mode uses WildFly Source-to-Image (S2I) Builder and Runtime images to create the application image.
In the &lt;code&gt;bootable-jar&lt;/code&gt; build mode, the &lt;code&gt;BuildConfig&lt;/code&gt; will compile the application as a Bootable Jar and use the OpenJDK 11 image as the base image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally there is an &lt;code&gt;env&lt;/code&gt; section that contains any environment variables needed to &lt;strong&gt;build&lt;/strong&gt; the image. We have three environment variables that are needed for Maven options.
As a whole they mean that we build only the specific &lt;code&gt;microprofile-config&lt;/code&gt; Maven module from the quickstart Git repository with the &lt;code&gt;bootable-jar-openshift&lt;/code&gt; Maven Profile (to create a Bootable Jar) and use its artifact as the target of the application image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; section focuses on deploying the application image on OpenShift. It creates different resources (&lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;, one or many &lt;code&gt;Services&lt;/code&gt;, a &lt;code&gt;Route&lt;/code&gt;) to make the application accessible from inside and outside the cluster by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have only defined two fields in that section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;replicas&lt;/code&gt; which specifies the number of pods that the application will use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;env&lt;/code&gt; wich are environment variables needed to &lt;strong&gt;run&lt;/strong&gt; the image. In our example, we only have one named &lt;code&gt;CONFIG_PROP&lt;/code&gt; and its value is used in the HTTP endpoint&amp;#8217;s response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things to discuss with this chart and we will have other blog posts to showcase its features.
All of them are documented in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/blob/main/charts/wildfly/README.md&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wildfly&lt;/code&gt; Chart documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However as a last example, one of the interesting features of Helm is that the YAML configuration file can be overridden on the command line to provide additional customization to the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To highlight this, we will &lt;strong&gt;upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; the application by changing the number of replicas of the applications so that we have &lt;code&gt;3&lt;/code&gt; pods instead of &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; (by setting the &lt;code&gt;deploy.replicas&lt;/code&gt; field to 3 with the &lt;code&gt;helm upgrade&lt;/code&gt; command)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-nowrap&quot; data-lang=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;$ helm upgrade microprofile-config-app \
    wildfly/wildfly \
    -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/main/examples/microprofile-config/microprofile-config-app.yaml \
    --set deploy.replicas=3
Release &quot;microprofile-config-app&quot; has been upgraded. Happy Helming!
NAME: microprofile-config-app
LAST DEPLOYED: Tue May  4 15:21:29 2021
NAMESPACE: jmesnil1-dev
STATUS: deployed
REVISION: 2
TEST SUITE: None
NOTES:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we watch the deployment, we see that the application is now scaling up to 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ oc get deployment microprofile-config-app -w
NAME                      READY   UP-TO-DATE   AVAILABLE   AGE
microprofile-config-app   1/3     3            1           29m
microprofile-config-app   2/3     3            2           30m
microprofile-config-app   3/3     3            3           30m&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Helm Chart for WildFly simplifies building and deploying WildFly application on OpenShift and Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;code&gt;wildfly&lt;/code&gt; Chart is designed to leverage WildFly features (such as Bootable Jar, Galleon provisioning, S2I) to make sure WildFly applications can be deployed and maintained on OpenShift with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-information&quot;&gt;More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://helm.sh&quot;&gt;Helm - The package manager for Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts&quot;&gt;wildfly-charts Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/wildfly-charts/blob/main/charts/wildfly/README.md&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wildfly&lt;/code&gt; Chart documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.redhat.com/developer-sandbox&quot;&gt;Developer Sandbox for Red Hat OpenShift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/bootablejar/&quot;&gt;WildFly Bootable Jar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Jeff Mesnil</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="wildfly" />
      
        <category term="openshift" />
      
        <category term="helm" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Helm is a tool that helps define, install and upgrade complex applications on Kubernetes clusters.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">WildFly 23.0.2 is released!</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/04/29/WildFly2302-Released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WildFly 23.0.2 is released!" />
      <published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/04/29/WildFly2302-Released</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/04/29/WildFly2302-Released/">&lt;div id=&quot;preamble&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly 23.0.2.Final is now available &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildfly.org/downloads&quot;&gt;for download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the release of Jakarta EE 9 the Jakarta EE Platform Project has been busy with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eclipse-ee4j.github.io/jakartaee-platform/jakartaee9/JakartaEE9.1ReleasePlan&quot;&gt;Jakarta EE 9.1 Release&lt;/a&gt;.  This has now progressed to the point that a candidate release of the Jakarta EE 9.1 TCK is available with WildFly 23.0.2.Final being our release candidate as a compatible implementation based on this TCK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wildfly-preview-and-jakarta-ee-9&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview and Jakarta EE 9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/23/WildFly_and_WildFly_Preview.html&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview variant&lt;/a&gt; of the server still passes the Jakarta EE 9 for the TCKs &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9/WildFly_23.0.2.Final/jakarta-full-platform.adoc&quot;&gt;Full Platform&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9/WildFly_23.0.2.Final/jakarta-web-profile.adoc&quot;&gt;Web Profile&lt;/a&gt;.  We have previously sent a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/326&quot;&gt;compatibility certification request for the Full Platform&lt;/a&gt; for WildFly Preview 23.0.1.Final and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/315&quot;&gt;compatibility certification request for the Web Profile&lt;/a&gt; for WildFly Preview 23.0.0.Final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once released, Jakarta EE 9.1 will be the first Jakarta EE release that allows a server to certify using both Java 8 and Java 11 for both the web profile and the full platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the various permutations we have published the following test results using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/23/WildFly_and_WildFly_Preview.html&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview variant&lt;/a&gt; of the server with the candidate release of the Jakarta EE 9.1 TCKs and submitted corresponding certification requests to Eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9.1/WildFly_23.0.2.Final/jakarta-web-profile-jdk8.adoc&quot;&gt;Test Results - Web Profile - Java 8&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/349&quot;&gt;Certification Request - Web Profile - Java 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9.1/WildFly_23.0.2.Final/jakarta-web-profile.adoc&quot;&gt;Test Results - Web Profile - Java 11&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/347&quot;&gt;Certification Request - Web Profile - Java 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9.1/WildFly_23.0.2.Final/jakarta-full-platform-jdk8.adoc&quot;&gt;Test Results - Full Platform - Java 8&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/348&quot;&gt;Certification Request - Full Platform - Java 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9.1/WildFly_23.0.2.Final/jakarta-full-platform.adoc&quot;&gt;Test Results - Full Platform - Java 11&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/346&quot;&gt;Certification Request - Full Platform - Java 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hopeful this will mean the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/23/WildFly_and_WildFly_Preview.html&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview variant&lt;/a&gt; of the server can be declared compatible with Jakarta EE 9.1 at the time it is released for the Web Profile and Full Platform against both Java 8 and Java 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a busy couple of weeks working through the remaining issues to pass the candidate release of the Jakarta EE Platform 9.1 TCKs with particular thanks to Brian Stansberry, Scott Marlow, Richard Opalka, Jean-Francois Denise, Tomasz Adamski, Jim Ma, and Alessio Soldano for making it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is described in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/23/WildFly_and_WildFly_Preview.html&quot;&gt;WildFly docs&lt;/a&gt;, WildFly Preview is a tech preview variant of the server meant to allow our community to get an early look at new things we&amp;#8217;re looking to eventually bring into the standard WildFly variant. Currently, the main (but not only) difference from standard WildFly is support of Jakarta EE 9 and 9.1 instead of EE 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly Preview is not a compatible Jakarta EE 8 or MicroProfile Platform 4.0 implementation, although we do expect most apps using the EE 8 and MP 4 APIs to run well on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly Preview is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildfly.org/downloads&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;, next to the standard WildFly download links for the same version. Look for the 'WildFly Preview EE 9 Distribution' links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;release-notes&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of issues resolved in WildFly 23.0.2 is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12313721&amp;amp;version=12356561&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. WildFly 23.0.2.Final is using the same version of WildFly Core as was used in the 23.0.1.Final release so no WildFly Core specific fixes have been applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Darran Lofthouse</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="announcement" />
      
        <category term="release" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">WildFly 23.0.2.Final is now available for download.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">WildFly 23.0.1 is released!</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/04/14/WildFly2301-Released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WildFly 23.0.1 is released!" />
      <published>2021-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/04/14/WildFly2301-Released</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/04/14/WildFly2301-Released/">&lt;div id=&quot;preamble&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly 23.0.1.Final is now available &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildfly.org/downloads&quot;&gt;for download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been about a month since the WildFly 23 release, so we&amp;#8217;ve done a bug fix update, WildFly 23.0.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wildfly-preview-and-jakarta-ee-9-0&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview and Jakarta EE 9.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big news in this release is the fact that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/23/WildFly_and_WildFly_Preview.html&quot;&gt;WildFly Preview variant&lt;/a&gt; of the server passes the TCKs for the Jakarta EE 9.0 &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9/WildFly_23.0.1.Final/jakarta-full-platform.adoc&quot;&gt;Full Platform&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wildfly/certifications/blob/EE9/WildFly_23.0.1.Final/jakarta-web-profile.adoc&quot;&gt;Web Profile&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#8217;ve sent a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/326&quot;&gt;compatibility certification request for the Full Platform&lt;/a&gt; to Eclipse. We&amp;#8217;d previously been able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-ee4j/jakartaee-platform/issues/315&quot;&gt;certify compatibility with the Web Profile&lt;/a&gt; for WildFly Preview 23.0.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m very excited about this achievement and am so proud of the great WildFly contributors who made it happen, particularly Scott Marlow, Richard Opalka, Jean-Francois Denise, Geoffrey DeSmet, Emmanuel Hugonnet, Farah Juma, Jason Lee, Jim Ma, Matej Novotny, Flavia Rainone and Parul Sharma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is described in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.wildfly.org/23/WildFly_and_WildFly_Preview.html&quot;&gt;WildFly docs&lt;/a&gt;, WildFly Preview is a tech preview variant of the server meant to allow our community to get an early look at new things we&amp;#8217;re looking to eventually bring into the standard WildFly variant. Currently, the main (but not only) difference from standard WildFly is support of Jakarta EE 9 instead of EE 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly Preview is not a compatible Jakarta EE 8 or MicroProfile Platform 4.0 implementation, although we do expect most apps using the EE 8 and MP 4 APIs to run well on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WildFly Preview is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildfly.org/downloads&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;, next to the standard WildFly download links for the same version. Look for the 'WildFly Preview EE 9 Distribution' links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;release-notes&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of issues resolved in WildFly 23.0.1 is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12313721&amp;amp;version=12354096&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Issues resolved in the WildFly Core update included with WildFly 23.0.1 are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12315422&amp;amp;version=12354209&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Brian Stansberry</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="announcement" />
      
        <category term="release" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">WildFly 23.0.1.Final is now available for download.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">WildFly Encrypted Expression Support</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/wildfly-encrypted-expressions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WildFly Encrypted Expression Support" />
      <published>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/wildfly-encrypted-expressions/</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/wildfly-encrypted-expressions/"></content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Darran Lofthouse</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="elytron" />
      
        <category term="wildfly" />
      
        <category term="encryption" />
      
        <category term="aes" />
      
        <category term="expression" />
      
        <category term="management-model" />
      

      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Upcoming hash character sets and hash encodings support in Elytron</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/upcoming-hash-encodings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upcoming hash character sets and hash encodings support in Elytron" />
      <published>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/upcoming-hash-encodings/</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/upcoming-hash-encodings/"></content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Sonia Zaldana Calles</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="wildfly" />
      
        <category term="elytron" />
      

      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Upcoming SSLContext that supports delegation to alternate instances based on peer information</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/sslcontext-delegation-to-alternate-instances-based-on-peer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upcoming SSLContext that supports delegation to alternate instances based on peer information" />
      <published>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/sslcontext-delegation-to-alternate-instances-based-on-peer/</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/sslcontext-delegation-to-alternate-instances-based-on-peer/"></content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Diana Krepinska Vilkolakova</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="elytron" />
      
        <category term="wildfly23" />
      
        <category term="ssl" />
      
        <category term="context" />
      
        <category term="delegation" />
      
        <category term="dynamic" />
      
        <category term="peer" />
      
        <category term="information" />
      

      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Normalize principal propagation/injection across elytron and legacy</title>
      <link href="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/normalization-of-EJB-principal-propagation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Normalize principal propagation/injection across elytron and legacy" />
      <published>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/normalization-of-EJB-principal-propagation/</id>
      
      
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/normalization-of-EJB-principal-propagation/"></content>
      

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
        <name>Diana Krepinska Vilkolakova</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        
      

      
        <category term="elytron" />
      
        <category term="wildfly23" />
      
        <category term="ejb" />
      
        <category term="principal" />
      
        <category term="propagation" />
      
        <category term="authentication" />
      

      

      
      
    </entry>
  

</feed>

